<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: baseliner -->
  <Baseliner.label>humain</Baseliner.label>
  <!-- EN: A naturally-evolved human with no major significant genetic modifications. -->
  <Baseliner.description>Un humain naturellement évolué sans modifications génétiques significatives majeures.</Baseliner.description>
  
  <!-- EN: dirtmole -->
  <Dirtmole.label>homme-taupe</Dirtmole.label>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, they thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are extremely capable at digging or mining tasks. In the open, however, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance.\n\nAfter the first tunnel colonies failed due to the stress of confinement, colonization agencies began genetically altering colonists to live without open space or sunlight. This xenotype are known colloquially as dirtmoles. Today, dirtmoles have expanded out of their original tunnel homes and rule many confined spaces in the anthrosphere. They can be found in deep mines, cramped low-tech spacecraft, and teeming by the billions in the dark underlayers of countless urbworlds. -->
  <Dirtmole.description>Avec une peau grise adaptée à la lumière artificielle, ils prospèrent dans des espaces exigus et sombres où les combats et les déplacements se déroulent sur de courtes distances. Ils sont extrêmement capables dans les tâches comme creuser ou extraire. En plein air, cependant, ils souffrent d'une sensibilité à la lumière, d'une vitesse lente et d'une mauvaise vue à distance.\n\nAprès l'échec des premières colonies souterraines en raison du stress du confinement, les agences de colonisation ont commencé à modifier génétiquement les colons à la vie sans espace ouvert ni lumière du soleil. Ce xénotype est connu familièrement sous le nom d'hommes-taupes. Aujourd'hui, les hommes-taupes se sont développées hors de leurs tunnels d'origine et règnent sur de nombreux espaces confinés de l'Anthrosphère. Ils peuvent être trouvés dans de profondes mines, des vaisseaux spatiaux vétustes et exigus ou grouillant par milliards dans les sous-niveaux sombres d'innombrables mondes urbains.</Dirtmole.description>
  <!-- EN: With gray skin adapted to artificial light, dirtmoles thrive in cramped and dark spaces where combat and travel happen over short distances. They are naturals at digging and navigating complex tunnel structures. In the open, they suffer from a sensitivity to light, slow speed and poor eyesight at distance. -->
  <Dirtmole.descriptionShort>Avec une peau grise adaptée à la lumière artificielle, les hommes-taupes prospèrent dans des espaces exigus et sombres où les combats et les déplacements se déroulent sur de courtes distances. Ils sont doués pour creuser et naviguer dans des structures de tunnel complexes. En plein air, ils souffrent d'une sensibilité à la lumière, d'une vitesse lente et d'une mauvaise vue à distance.</Dirtmole.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: genie -->
  <Genie.label>savant</Genie.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies' delicate bones and natural aptitude with machines allow them to manipulate devices with remarkable precision. They are emotionally cold and can follow orders where others might panic. However, they are fragile, and their amplified nerve impulses make them easy to debilitate with relatively little pain. With so much of their brains dedicated to analyzing machines, they lack the neural hardware to analyze emotions, so they sometimes come off as socially inept. Their dead calm makes it even harder for them to relate to what they see as madly-hotheaded baseliner humans.\n\nGenies were engineered thousands of years ago by a long-disbanded space navy to hold engineering positions on large starships. Today, genies still serve as engineers in great cities and fleets, but many can also be found working as lawyers, pilots, and musicians. -->
  <Genie.description>Conçus pour être des ingénieurs, les os délicats des savants et leur aptitude naturelle pour les machines leur permettent de manipuler des appareils avec une précision remarquable. Ils sont émotionnellement froids et peuvent suivre des ordres là où d'autres pourraient paniquer. Cependant, ils sont fragiles et leurs impulsions nerveuses amplifiées les rendent faciles à affaiblir avec relativement peu de douleur. Avec une si grande partie de leur cerveau consacrée à l'analyse des machines, ils n'ont pas le matériel neuronal pour analyser les émotions, de sorte qu'ils parfois présentés comme socialement inaptes. Leur calme plat rend encore plus difficile pour eux de se lier à ce qu'ils considèrent comme des humains de base à la tête folle.\n\nLes savants ont été conçus il y a des milliers d'années par une marine spatiale dissoute depuis longtemps pour occuper des postes d'ingénierie sur de grands vaisseaux spatiaux. Aujourd'hui, les savants servent encore d'ingénieurs dans les grandes villes et les grandes flottes, mais beaucoup travaillent également comme avocats, pilotes et musiciens.</Genie.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed to be engineers, genies have natural aptitude with machines, and are emotionally cold and calm. They are also fragile and vulnerable to pain. Focused on machines, they often come off as socially inept. -->
  <Genie.descriptionShort>Conçus pour être des ingénieurs, les savants ont des aptitudes naturelles pour les machines et sont émotionnellement froids et calmes. Ils sont également fragiles et vulnérables à la douleur. Focalisés sur les machines, ils se révèlent souvent socialement inaptes.</Genie.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: highmate -->
  <Highmate.label>psycharmeur</Highmate.label>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence.\n\nOn a few wealthy worlds, highmate xenogerms are commercially available and some people become highmates as a sort of career. However, many societies find them abhorrent, either because they distract people from forming natural families, or because they are humans shaped to serve the pleasures of another. On such worlds they are either reserved as playthings of the powerful, or banned entirely. This particular line of highmate fits the fashions of classical Novaroma, but many other variants exist. -->
  <Highmate.description>Compagnons et concubines conçus avec une capacité unique à se lier psychiquement à quelq'un, les psycharmeurs sont empathiques, beaux, joyeux et talentueux sur le plan sociale. Ils sont également incompétents pour les tâches manuelles, physiquement faibles et mentalement incapables de violence.\n\nSur quelques mondes riches, les xénogermes psycharmeur sont disponibles dans le commerce et certaines personnes choisissent comme plan de carrière de devenir des psycharmeurs. Cependant, de nombreuses sociétés les trouvent odieux, soit parce qu'ils empêchent les gens de former des familles naturelles, soit parce qu'ils sont des humains façonnés pour servir les plaisirs d'autrui. Sur de tels mondes, ils sont soit réservés comme jouets des puissants, soit totalement interdits. Cette ligne particulière de psycharmeurs correspond à la mode du Novaroma classique, mais de nombreuses autres variantes existent.</Highmate.description>
  <!-- EN: Designed companions and concubines with a unique ability to psychically bond with a mate, highmates are empathic, beautiful, cheerful, and talented in social matters. They are also inept at manual tasks, physically weak, and mentally incapable of violence. -->
  <Highmate.descriptionShort>Compagnons et concubines conçus avec une capacité unique à se lier psychiquement à quelq'un, les psycharmeurs sont empathiques, beaux, joyeux et talentueux en matière sociale. Ils sont également inaptes aux tâches manuelles, physiquement faibles et mentalement incapables de violence.</Highmate.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: hussar -->
  <Hussar.label>hussard</Hussar.label>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice, which also makes them less likely to rebel against their commanders.\n\nWhile hussars' emotions make them dangerous in combat, they can't relate to baseliner humans. They are famous for their blood-red eyes and "hussar stare", a dead expression that unsettles many people. Their lack of expression and burning aggressive nature has led to many violent misunderstandings.\n\nIn most societies where they live, hussars are kept separated from the rest of the population. Hussars are single-purpose tools - and they generally aren't bothered by the fact. -->
  <Hussar.description>Les hussards sont des soldats génétiques. Ils combattent agressivement et avec précision, guérissent rapidement, prospèrent dans les températures extrêmes et ingèrent librement des stimulants militaires. Ils ont une dépendance génétique au go-juice, ce qui les rend également moins susceptibles de se rebeller contre leurs commandants.\n\nBien que les émotions des hussards les rendent dangereux au combat, ils ne peuvent pas s'identifier aux humains de base. Ils sont célèbres pour leurs yeux rouge sang et leur "regard de hussard", une expression vide qui dérange beaucoup de gens. Leur manque d'expression et leur agressivité brûlante ont conduit à de nombreux malentendus violents.\n\nDans la plupart des sociétés où ils vivent, les hussards sont séparés du reste de la population. Les hussards sont des outils à usage unique, ils ne sont généralement pas dérangés par cet état de fait.</Hussar.description>
  <!-- EN: Hussars are engineered soldiers. They fight aggressively and with precision, heal fast, thrive in extreme temperatures, and freely ingest military drugs. They have a genetic dependence on go-juice. -->
  <Hussar.descriptionShort>Les hussards sont des soldats génétiques Ils combattent agressivement et avec précision, guérissent rapidement, prospèrent dans les températures extrêmes et ingèrent librement des stimulants militaires. Ils ont une dépendance génétique au go-juice.</Hussar.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: impid -->
  <Impid.label>diabloïde</Impid.label>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impid cultures live on many rimworlds and dry deathworlds. Impids are extremely fast-moving, easily tolerate high temperatures, and can spew fire from their mouths. Though they are masters on the sand, impids struggle in other environments. They are terrible with farming. They fight well at range, but in close combat their physical weakness becomes apparent.\n\nOutlanders call them dustrunners because of their speed over open terrain and resistance to heat. Some tribes call them devils because of their horns and because they burn their enemies. Impid tribes' combat tactics usually center on rapid-approach incendiary attacks using both handheld fire weapons and their fire spew ability. -->
  <Impid.description>Conçues pour la vie dans le désert, les cultures diabloïdes vivent sur de nombreux mondes périphériques et des mondes de désertiques. Les diabloïdes se déplacent extrêmement rapidement, tolèrent facilement les températures élevées et peuvent cracher du feu par la bouche. Bien qu'ils soient des maîtres sur le sable, les diabloïdes peinnent dans les autres environnements. Ils sont épouventables en agriculture. Ils se battent bien à distance, mais au corps à corps, leur faiblesse physique devient évidente.\n\nLes étrangers les appellent des coureurs de poussière en raison de leur vitesse en terrain découvert et de leur résistance à la chaleur. Certaines tribus les appellent des démons à cause de leurs cornes et parce qu'ils brûlent leurs ennemis. Les tactiques de combat des tribus diablïdes se concentrent généralement sur des attaques incendiaires à approche rapide utilisant à la fois des armes à feu portatives et leur capacité à cracher du feu.</Impid.description>
  <!-- EN: Made for desert life, impids are very fast, can spew fire from their mouths, and easily tolerate high temperatures. They fight well at range, but in close combat they do little damage. They are terrible with farming, and have weak immune systems. -->
  <Impid.descriptionShort>Conçus pour la vie dans le désert, les diabloïdes sont très rapides, peuvent cracher du feu de leur bouche et tolèrent facilement les températures élevées. Ils se battent bien à distance, mais en combat rapproché, ils font peu de dégâts. Ils sont épouventables en agriculture et ont un système immunitaire faible.</Impid.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: neanderthal -->
  <Neanderthal.label>néandertalien</Neanderthal.label>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. Their most salient characteristic is that they are difficult to hurt: They are very resistant to injury, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, without ever having evolved in a complex civilization, they are less adept than baseliner humans at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis was originally an archaic population of hominids that emerged over 200,000 years ago during the Pleistocene epoch. After they were replaced by and merged with humans 30,000 years ago, they were absent for tens of thousands of years until scientists resurrected them from ancient DNA. Neanderthals now survive in sub-societies on some settled planets. On the rimworlds, neanderthal tribes carve out the same existence as their Earth ancestors did so long ago. -->
  <Neanderthal.description>Les néandertaliens sont des humanoïdes trapus et puissamment bâtis. Leur caractéristique la plus saillante est qu'ils sont difficiles à blesser : ils sont très résistants aux blessures et leur système immunitaire puissant les protège des infections. Cependant, sans jamais avoir évolué dans une civilisation complexe, ils sont moins aptes que les humains de base pour les tâches intellectuelles et sociales, et leur impulsivité peut les rendre dangereusement agressifs.\n\nHomo neanderthalensis était à l'origine une population archaïque d'hominidés apparue il y a plus de 200 000 ans à l'époque du Pléistocène. Après avoir été remplacés et fusionnés avec les humains il y a 30 000 ans, ils ont été absents pendant des dizaines de milliers d'années jusqu'à ce que les scientifiques les ressuscitent à partir d'ADN ancien. Les Néandertaliens survivent maintenant en sous-sociétés sur certaines planètes colonisées. Sur les mondes périphériques, les tribus néandertaliennes mènent la même existence que leurs ancêtres terrestres il y a si longtemps.</Neanderthal.description>
  <!-- EN: Neanderthals are stocky, powerfully-built humanoids. They are hardy and difficult to injure, and their strong immune systems protect them from infection. However, their minds are less adept at intellectual and social tasks, and their impulsiveness can make them dangerously aggressive. -->
  <Neanderthal.descriptionShort>Les néandertaliens sont des humanoïdes trapus et puissamment construits. Ils sont robustes et difficiles à blesser, et leur système immunitaire fort les protège des infections. Cependant, leur esprit est moins apte aux tâches intellectuelles et sociales, et leur impulsivité peut les rendre dangereusement agressifs.</Neanderthal.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: pigskin -->
  <Pigskin.label>homme-cochon</Pigskin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids which are capable of two-legged movement, tool use, and speech, but which also retain many pig-like qualities. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands leave them at a disadvantage when attempting to precisely manipulate tools and objects. They don't see well at a distance, so pigskin gangs usually focus on close-range weapons. They also have a strong taste for explosives.\n\nPigskins were made for their organs. Uncomfortable with the idea of harvesting organs from baseliner humans, a long-gone government merged human DNA into pigs to make the animals produce more easily-transplantable hearts and lungs. They succeeded, but the resulting creatures became more humanlike than anyone anticipated. -->
  <Pigskin.description>Les hommes-cochons sont des hybrides humains-porcs capables de mouvement à deux pattes, d'utilisation d'outils et de parole, mais qui conservent également de nombreuses qualités de porc. Ils sont robustes et peuvent manger presque n'importe quoi sans tomber malade, mais leurs mains en forme de sabots les désavantagent lorsqu'ils tentent de manipuler avec précision des outils et des objets. Ils ne voient pas bien à distance, donc les gangs d'hommes-cochons se concentrent généralement sur les armes à courte portée. Ils ont aussi un goût prononcé pour les explosifs.\n\nLes hommes-cochons ont été conçus pour leurs organes. Mal à l'aise avec l'idée de prélever des organes sur des humains de base, un gouvernement oublié a fusionné l'ADN humain avec celui des porcs pour que les animaux produisent des cœurs et des poumons plus facilement transplantables. Ils ont réussi, mais les créatures résultantes sont devenues plus humaines que quiconque ne l'avait prévu.</Pigskin.description>
  <!-- EN: Pigskins are human-pig hybrids. They are hardy and can eat almost anything without getting sick, but their trotter-shaped hands are bad at fine manipulation. They don't see well at a distance, so they usually focus on close-range weapons. They have a strong taste for explosives. -->
  <Pigskin.descriptionShort>Les hommes-cochons sont des hybrides humain-porc. Ils sont robustes et peuvent manger presque n'importe quoi sans tomber malade, mais leurs mains en forme de sabots sont mauvaises pour les manipulations fines. Ils ne voient pas bien à distance, ils se concentrent donc généralement sur les armes à courte portée. Ils ont un goût prononcé pour les explosifs.</Pigskin.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: sanguophage -->
  <Sanguophage.label>sanguophage</Sanguophage.label>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are a type of archotech-enhanced xenohuman. Powered by archites, their abilities go far beyond normal genetic enhancements. They are mentally adept and preternaturally beautiful. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. They don't age or die naturally and never suffer from disease or poison. A sanguophage can make a new sanguophage by reimplanting their own xenogerm into a person.\n\nSanguophages must regularly consume hemogen derived from human blood, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light.\n\nThe first sanguophage appeared thousands of years ago when the lord-explorer Varan-Dur sought to control a hyperintelligent archotech and found himself transformed by it instead. Every sanguophage is descended from him. Since then, sanguophages have often been hunted because of their destabilizing power and their need for blood. Since they can pass for baseliners, many live in hiding among typical humans.\n\nTheir numbers are unknown. Some think they are legends or rare irrelevancies. Some believe sanguophages secretly direct entire human civilizations. The stories speak of eternal lords ruling billions from slate-black space stations, or directing blood sacrifices at conferences in the underlayers of the deepest urbworlds. -->
  <Sanguophage.description>Les sanguophages sont un type de xénohumain amélioré par l'archotech. Améliorés par des archites, leurs capacités vont bien au-delà des améliorations génétiques normales. Ils sont mentalement habiles et d'une beauté surnaturelle. Au combat, ils peuvent lancer des épines mortelles et soigner des amis blessés. Ils ne vieillissent pas ou ne meurent pas naturellement et ne souffrent jamais de maladie ou de poison. Un sanguophage peut créer un nouveau sanguophage en réimplantant son propre xénogerme dans la personne.\n\nLes sanguophages doivent régulièrement consommer de l'hémogène dérivé du sang humain, et ils doivent périodiquement subir le repos de la mort pendant de longues périodes. Ils sont facilement détruits par le feu et ralentis par la lumière UV.\n\nLe premier sanguophage est apparu il y a des milliers d'années lorsque le seigneur-explorateur Varan-Dur a cherché à contrôler un archotech hyperintelligent et s'est finalement retrouvé transformé par lui à la place. Tout sanguophage descend de lui. Depuis, les sanguophages sont souvent chassés en raison de leur pouvoir déstabilisateur et de leur besoin de sang. Puisqu'ils peuvent passer pour des basiques, beaucoup vivent cachés parmi des humains typiques.\n\nLeur nombre est inconnu. Certains pensent qu'il s'agit de légendes ou d'incongruités rares. Certains croient que les sanguophages dirigent secrètement des civilisations humaines entières. Les histoires parlent de seigneurs éternels gouvernant des milliards d'individus depuis des stations spatiales noires comme de l'ardoise, ou dirigeant des sacrifices sanglants lors de réunions secrètes dans les sous-niveaux les plus profonds des mondes urbains.</Sanguophage.description>
  <!-- EN: Sanguophages are ageless, deathless super-humans powered by archotech-created archites in the bloodstream. They are beautiful and extremely intelligent. They can heal any injury, and never suffer from disease or poison. In combat, they can launch deadly spines and heal injured friends. The price is that sanguophages must consume hemogen derived from human blood to survive, and they must periodically deathrest for long periods. They're easily destroyed by fire, and slowed down by UV light. -->
  <Sanguophage.descriptionShort>Les sanguophages sont des surhumains sans âge et immortel alimentés par des archites sanguines créés par des archotech. Ils sont beaux et extrêmement intelligents. Ils peuvent guérir de n'importe quelle blessure et ne souffrent jamais de maladie ou de poison. Au combat, ils peuvent lancer des épines mortelles et soigner des amis blessés. Le prix a payer est que les sanguophages doivent consommer de l'hémogène dérivé du sang humain pour survivre, et ils doivent périodiquement se reposer pendant de longues périodes. Ils sont facilement détruits par le feu et ralentis par la lumière UV.</Sanguophage.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: waster -->
  <Waster.label>pestilent</Waster.label>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo.\n\nOriginally engineered to prevent resettlement of post-apocalyptic deathworlds, wasters are living area-denial weapons. Waster pirates armed with toxic weapons are the bane of many frontier peoples, both on the rimworlds and in the depths of the urbworld hyperstructures. -->
  <Waster.description>Les pestilents sont agressifs, immunisés contre la pollution toxique, presque insensibles aux maladies, et peuvent ingérer autant de psychoïdes et de wake-up qu'ils le souhaitent sans effets nocifs. Leur métabolisme adapté aux toxines signifie qu'ils doivent consommer une certaine forme de psychoïde - généralement du flake ou du yayo.\n\nConçus à l'origine pour empêcher la récolonisation des mondes morts post-apocalyptiques, les pestilents sont des armes de déni de zone de vie. Les pirates pestilents armés d'armes toxiques sont le fléau de nombreux peuples frontaliers, à la fois sur les mondes périphériques et dans les profondeurs des hyperstructures de mondes urbains.</Waster.description>
  <!-- EN: Wasters are aggressive, immune to toxic pollution, almost impervious to disease, and can ingest as much psychite and wake-up drugs as they wish with no ill effects. Their toxin-adapted metabolism means they must consume some form of psychite - usually flake or yayo. -->
  <Waster.descriptionShort>Les pestilents sont agressifs, immunisés contre la pollution toxique, presque insensibles aux maladies, et peuvent ingérer autant de psychoïdes et de wake-up qu'ils le souhaitent sans effets nocifs. Leur métabolisme adapté aux toxines signifie qu'ils doivent consommer une forme de psychoïde, généralement du flake ou du yayo.</Waster.descriptionShort>
  
  <!-- EN: yttakin -->
  <Yttakin.label>yttakin</Yttakin.label>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments. Yttakin share a psychic connection with the wildlife and can summon animals to their side during battles. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before.\n\nSince they migrated off their icy birthworld of Yttak, Yttakin settlements live on many planets. Their fur, roaring voices, and aversion to urban living sometimes leads naive outsiders to believe they are simple-minded animals. Quick-minded Yttakin are happy to make good use of such wrong beliefs, whether at the negotiating table or on the battlefield. -->
  <Yttakin.description>Les yttakin descendent de colons conçus pour prospérer sur des planètes ultra-froides. Leur grande taille et leur fourrure les rendent robustes dans les environnements gelés. Les Yttakin partagent une connexion psychique avec la faune et peuvent invoquer des animaux à leurs côtés pendant les batailles. Ils ne sont ni rapides, ni puissants, ni précis, mais peuvent continuer alors que d'autres se seraient effondrés depuis longtemps.\n\nDepuis qu'ils ont quitté leur monde glacial d'Yttak, les colonies d'Yttakin se développent sur de nombreuses planètes. Leur fourrure, leurs voix rugissantes et leur aversion pour la vie urbaine amènent parfois les étrangers naïfs à croire qu'ils ne sont que des animaux simples d'esprit. Les Yttakin à l'esprit vif sont heureux de faire bon usage de ces fausses croyances, que ce soit à la table des négociations ou sur le champ de bataille.</Yttakin.description>
  <!-- EN: Yttakin descend from colonists engineered to thrive on ultra-cold planets. Their great size and fur make them hardy in frozen environments, and they have a unique ability to communicate vocally and psychically with animals. They are not fast or energetic or precise, but can keep going when others would have collapsed long before. -->
  <Yttakin.descriptionShort>Les yttakin descendent de colons conçus pour prospérer sur des planètes ultra-froides. Leur grande taille et leur fourrure les rendent robustes dans les environnements gelés, et ils ont une capacité unique à communiquer vocalement et psychiquement avec les animaux. Ils ne sont ni rapides, ni puissants, ni précis, mais peuvent continuer alors que d'autres se seraient effondrés depuis longtemps.</Yttakin.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>