<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <Apparel_CowboyHat.label>cowboy hat</Apparel_CowboyHat.label>
  <Apparel_CowboyHat.description>Stylish yet rugged, this hat keeps the sun and rain off - and it gives anyone who wears it a bit of extra charm. It is the most important part of traditional western attire.</Apparel_CowboyHat.description>

  <Apparel_BowlerHat.label>bowler hat</Apparel_BowlerHat.label>
  <Apparel_BowlerHat.description>A good-looking hat which projects a slightly urban, money-loving style. Improves social impact.</Apparel_BowlerHat.description>

  <Apparel_TribalHeaddress.label>tribal headdress</Apparel_TribalHeaddress.label>
  <Apparel_TribalHeaddress.description>Elegant traditional garb, often with religious significance. Improves social impact.</Apparel_TribalHeaddress.description>

  <Apparel_Tuque.label>tuque</Apparel_Tuque.label>
  <Apparel_Tuque.description>A soft, thick cap. Great for keeping warm in winter.</Apparel_Tuque.description>

  <Apparel_WarMask.label>war mask</Apparel_WarMask.label>
  <Apparel_WarMask.description>An artistically terrifying war mask. Hides the wearer's face and makes them more confident.</Apparel_WarMask.description>

  <Apparel_WarVeil.label>war veil</Apparel_WarVeil.label>
  <Apparel_WarVeil.description>A war veil, made out of reinforced cloth torn to appear damaged in combat. Some believe this functions as a talisman of courage.</Apparel_WarVeil.description>


  <!-- Helmets -->

  <Apparel_SimpleHelmet.label>simple helmet</Apparel_SimpleHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_SimpleHelmet.description>A simple helmet which gives moderate protection against sharp attacks. Not effective against blunt weapons.</Apparel_SimpleHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_AdvancedHelmet.label>advanced helmet</Apparel_AdvancedHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_AdvancedHelmet.description>A lightweight combat helmet with a complex design, reinforced with plasteel. Not effective against blunt weapons.</Apparel_AdvancedHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_PowerArmorHelmet.label>power armor helmet</Apparel_PowerArmorHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_PowerArmorHelmet.description>A powered-armor helmet, with built-in status computer and layered plasteel armor. Usually used by heavy infantry and space marines in spacer-tech militaries.</Apparel_PowerArmorHelmet.description>

  <Apparel_PsychicFoilHelmet.label>psychic foil helmet</Apparel_PsychicFoilHelmet.label>
  <Apparel_PsychicFoilHelmet.description>A thin helmet containing finely-tuned sheets of psychically-absorptive foil. Reduces the impact of psychic waves.</Apparel_PsychicFoilHelmet.description>


</LanguageData>