<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

  <Beer.label>Bière</Beer.label>
  <Beer.description>La première boisson consommée par l'humanité, l'eau mise à part. La bière est bonne, mais provoque une intoxication. Trop en consommer peut provoquer une addiction.</Beer.description>
  <Beer.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Drink {0}</Beer.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <Beer.ingestible.ingestReportString>Drinking {0}.</Beer.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <Wort.label>moût</Wort.label>
  <Wort.description>Bière avant fermentation. Ce liquide doit être transféré dans un baril de fermentation avant qu'il ne devienne une bière buvable.</Wort.description>

  <WakeUp.label>wake-up</WakeUp.label>
  <WakeUp.description>An addictive stimulant. Fills the need for rest, and allows users to work for extended periods without getting tired. Addiction causes reduced mental performance and, sometimes, psychotic breaks with reality.</WakeUp.description>
  <WakeUp.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Take {0}</WakeUp.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <WakeUp.ingestible.ingestReportString>Taking {0}.</WakeUp.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <SmokeleafJoint.label>smokeleaf joint</SmokeleafJoint.label>
  <SmokeleafJoint.description>Smokeleaf leaves prepared in small rolls for smoking. The drug improves mood, but also increases appetite, reduces focus and slows movement. Smokeleaf use can produce a dependency. Can be produced without equipment, at a crafting spot.</SmokeleafJoint.description>
  <SmokeleafJoint.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Smoke {0}</SmokeleafJoint.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <SmokeleafJoint.ingestible.ingestReportString>Smoking {0}.</SmokeleafJoint.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <Flake.label>flake</Flake.label>
  <Flake.description>A flaky substance that can be smoked to induce a short but powerful euphoric state. While it is cheap to produce, it is exceptionally addictive.</Flake.description>
  <Flake.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Smoke {0}</Flake.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <Flake.ingestible.ingestReportString>Smoking {0}.</Flake.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <Yayo.label>yayo</Yayo.label>
  <Yayo.description>A fine white powder snorted to produce a euphoric high. Yayo reduces the user's need for rest, and suppresses pain. It is, however, addictive.</Yayo.description>
  <Yayo.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Snort {0}</Yayo.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <Yayo.ingestible.ingestReportString>Snorting {0}.</Yayo.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <GoJuice.label>go-juice</GoJuice.label>
  <GoJuice.description>A synthetic combat drug developed for space marines during the early days of interplanetary warfare. Go-juice blocks pain and increases the user's melee and shooting abilities. It also enhances movement speed.\n\nMilitary chemists who created it were never able to remove its addictiveness. Some saw this as a downside; others saw it as a benefit.</GoJuice.description>
  <GoJuice.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Inject {0}</GoJuice.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <GoJuice.ingestible.ingestReportString>Injecting {0}.</GoJuice.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <Penoxycyline.label>penoxycyline</Penoxycyline.label>
  <Penoxycyline.description>A drug for blocking various infections. Blocks malaria, sleeping sickness, and plague. Take every five days.</Penoxycyline.description>
  <Penoxycyline.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Take {0}</Penoxycyline.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <Penoxycyline.ingestible.ingestReportString>Taking {0}.</Penoxycyline.ingestible.ingestReportString>

  <Luciferium.label>luciferium</Luciferium.label>
  <Luciferium.description>A concoction of advanced glitterworld mechanites that dramatically improve the body's functioning in all respects. Unfortunately, without the moderating effects of regular doses every five or six days, the mechanites lose cohesion, causing continuous berserk rages and, eventually, death.\n\nAfter the first dose, there is no way to get the mechanites out, ever.\n\nOn the urbworlds, they call Luciferium the 'Devil's Bargain'. Many have been forced to kill friends when no more of the seductive red pills could be found.</Luciferium.description>
  <Luciferium.ingestible.ingestCommandString>Take {0}</Luciferium.ingestible.ingestCommandString>
  <Luciferium.ingestible.ingestReportString>Taking {0}.</Luciferium.ingestible.ingestReportString>


</LanguageData>
