<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <!-- Medicine -->

  <MedicineHerbal.label>herbal medicine</MedicineHerbal.label>
  <MedicineHerbal.description>A pack of herbal concoctions extracted from the healroot plant. It is less potent than industrial pharmaceuticals, but much better than nothing.</MedicineHerbal.description>

  <MedicineIndustrial.label>medicine</MedicineIndustrial.label>
  <MedicineIndustrial.description>A kit of industrial-era medical equipment. It contains basic drugs, tools for suturing and bone setting, diagnostic devices, and various pads and fluids.</MedicineIndustrial.description>

  <MedicineUltratech.label>glitterworld medicine</MedicineUltratech.label>
  <MedicineUltratech.description>A kit of advanced ultra-tech medical supplies, probably manufactured on a distant glitterworld. It contains advanced polymorphic drugs, nanite diagnostic and healing assisters, a mini-imager, and various multi-use tools.</MedicineUltratech.description>


  <!-- ComponentIndustrial -->

  <ComponentIndustrial.label>component</ComponentIndustrial.label>
  <ComponentIndustrial.description>Miscellaneous gears, capacitors, circuit boards, tubes, wheels, sensors, wires, chips, processors, and other electronic and industrial parts. Necessary for assembling complex machines or electronics.</ComponentIndustrial.description>

  <ComponentSpacer.label>advanced component</ComponentSpacer.label>
  <ComponentSpacer.description>Advanced computing and energy-directing machinery, miniaturized and hardened for the most demanding applications.</ComponentSpacer.description>


  <!-- Neutroamine -->

  <Neutroamine.label>neutroamine</Neutroamine.label>
  <Neutroamine.description>Un précurseur chimique synthétique. Inutilisable tel quel, c'est un ingrédient indispensable pour la fabrication des médicaments et de certaines drogues.</Neutroamine.description>


  <!-- Chemfuel -->

  <Chemfuel.label>chemfuel</Chemfuel.label>
  <Chemfuel.description>Composé chimique liquide volatile. Utilisé comme carburant pour les fusées et d'autres machines.</Chemfuel.description>


</LanguageData>
