<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <Peaceful.label>Pacifique</Peaceful.label>
  <Peaceful.description>Pour ceux qui veulent se détendre et construire une colonie dans un environnement de type bac à sable.\n\nLes événements très menaçants sont désactivés mais les colons peuvent toujours devenir râleurs et les animaux devenir fous de temps en temps.</Peaceful.description>

  <Easy.label>Un certain défi</Easy.label>
  <Easy.description>Pour les joueurs faisant leur première partie ou pour les joueurs occasionnels qui veulent un peu de défi.\n\nLes menaces sont dangereuses mais pas insurmontables.</Easy.description>

  <Medium.label>À la dure</Medium.label>
  <Medium.description>C'est une planète rude. Les menaces sont assez dangereuses. Non recommandé avant d'avoir une certaine expérience.</Medium.description>

  <Rough.label>Rough</Rough.label>
  <Rough.description>Struggle to survive on a rough, tough planet.\n\nRecommended for: Players with experience with RimWorld, looking to play an intense story requiring significant skill to survive.\n\nDo not expect to play a perfect clean game. You will lose people. Even if you play well, some challenges will be impossible to overcome without losses. You'll have to fight wounded, sacrifice to survive, and recover. It's all for the drama.</Rough.description>

  <Hard.label>Intense</Hard.label>
  <Hard.description>Un défi considérable. Réussir à ce niveau requiert une solide maîtrise des stratégies de survie, et d'avoir la chance de son côté.</Hard.description>

  <Extreme.label>Extreme</Extreme.label>
  <Extreme.description>Apply mastery of every RimWorld skill for just a chance to survive a harrowing trial against a cruel, unfair world.\n\nRecommended for: Players who want to face brutal, unfair situations that require the deployment of fluent and well-rounded skills and the sacrifice of treasured people just to avoid losing everything.\n\nThere is no clean game here. You'll spend a lot of time fighting wounded and recovering, you'll need to prepare carefully, and you'll need to sacrifice people and things you love. Unfair challenges and capricious death may come to you at any time. This level is about dealing with losses, because preventing them is impossible.</Extreme.description>


</LanguageData>
