<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <!-- Column 1 -->

  <PsychoidBrewing.label>psychoid brewing</PsychoidBrewing.label>
  <PsychoidBrewing.description>Prepare psychoid leaves into a mildly euphoria-inducing and addictive tea at the campfire or cooking stove.</PsychoidBrewing.description>

  <TreeSowing.label>tree sowing</TreeSowing.label>
  <TreeSowing.description>Sow the local biome's natural trees in your fields.</TreeSowing.description>

  <Brewing.label>beer brewing</Brewing.label>
  <Brewing.description>Build a brewery and fermenting vats to transform hops into tasty, tasty beer.</Brewing.description>

  <ComplexFurniture.label>complex furniture</ComplexFurniture.label>
  <ComplexFurniture.description>Build complex furniture like beds, end tables, dining chairs, armchairs, dressers, tool cabinets, billiard tables, and poker tables, vents, sarcophagi, and more.</ComplexFurniture.description>

  <PassiveCooler.label>passive cooler</PassiveCooler.label>
  <PassiveCooler.description>Make passive coolers, to cool indoor spaces without using electricity.</PassiveCooler.description>

  <Stonecutting.label>stonecutting</Stonecutting.label>
  <Stonecutting.description>Cut rock chunks into stone blocks for use in construction. Build beautiful stone tile floors or ugly concrete walkways.</Stonecutting.description>

  <ComplexClothing.label>complex clothing</ComplexClothing.label>
  <ComplexClothing.description>Tailor complicated garments like pants, dusters, and cowboy hats.</ComplexClothing.description>


  <!-- Column 2 -->

  <DrugProduction.label>drug production</DrugProduction.label>
  <DrugProduction.description>Build a drug lab for basic drug synthesis. Further research is required to make specific drugs.</DrugProduction.description>

  <Cocoa.label>cocoa</Cocoa.label>
  <Cocoa.description>Sow cocoa trees to create your own delicious chocolate. Eating chocolate fulfills the need for recreation, and it's valuable on the market too.</Cocoa.description>

  <Devilstrand.label>devilstrand</Devilstrand.label>
  <Devilstrand.description>Plant devilstrand, a slow-growing mushroom that yields an exceptionally tough, heat-resistant plant fiber.</Devilstrand.description>

  <CarpetMaking.label>carpet making</CarpetMaking.label>
  <CarpetMaking.description>Weave beautiful carpets from cloth.</CarpetMaking.description>

  <Pemmican.label>pemmican</Pemmican.label>
  <Pemmican.description>Make pemmican, a preserved mixture of meat and plant matter that doesn't go bad for a long time. Great for traveling.</Pemmican.description>


  <!-- Column 3+ -->

  <Smithing.label>smithing</Smithing.label>
  <Smithing.description>Build smithies for crafting metal weapons like knives, gladii, and maces. Work metal into clean, beautiful floor tiles.</Smithing.description>

  <RecurveBow.label>recurve bow</RecurveBow.label>
  <RecurveBow.description>Build the recurve bow, an effective and inexpensive ranged weapon.</RecurveBow.description>


  <!-- Drugs -->

  <PsychiteRefining.label>psychite refining</PsychiteRefining.label>
  <PsychiteRefining.description>Refine psychoid leaves into flake and yayo, different forms of the euphoric psychite drug.</PsychiteRefining.description>

  <WakeUpProduction.label>wake-up production</WakeUpProduction.label>
  <WakeUpProduction.description>Synthesize wake-up, a work performance-enhancing drug which replaces the need for sleep.</WakeUpProduction.description>

  <GoJuiceProduction.label>go-juice production</GoJuiceProduction.label>
  <GoJuiceProduction.description>Produce go-juice, a synthetic combat-performance-enhancing drug which improves shooting, melee, and movement ability, and dulls pain.</GoJuiceProduction.description>

  <PenoxycylineProduction.label>penoxycyline production</PenoxycylineProduction.label>
  <PenoxycylineProduction.description>Produce penoxycline, a disease prevention drug which blocks plague, malaria, and more before they start.</PenoxycylineProduction.description>


  <!-- Medieval weapons -->

  <LongBlades.label>long blades</LongBlades.label>
  <LongBlades.description>Craft longswords and spears.</LongBlades.description>

  <PlateArmor.label>plate armor</PlateArmor.label>
  <PlateArmor.description>Smith suits of plate armor from metal or wood. This heavy armor noticeably slows movement, but protects very effectively.</PlateArmor.description>

  <Greatbow.label>greatbow</Greatbow.label>
  <Greatbow.description>Craft greatbows for killing enemies at great range.</Greatbow.description>


</LanguageData>