<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <MultiAnalyzer.label>multi-analyzer</MultiAnalyzer.label>
  <MultiAnalyzer.description>Build multi-analyzers which increase research speed and allow higher-level research projects. Requires advanced components to construct.</MultiAnalyzer.description>

  <GroundPenetratingScanner.label>ground-penetrating scanner</GroundPenetratingScanner.label>
  <GroundPenetratingScanner.description>Build ground-penetrating scanners that can detect drillable resources under the surface. Requires advanced components to construct.</GroundPenetratingScanner.description>

  <DeepDrilling.label>deep drilling</DeepDrilling.label>
  <DeepDrilling.description>Build deep drills for extracting resources from underground. You'll need a ground-penetrating scanner to find the resources.</DeepDrilling.description>

  <VitalsMonitor.label>vitals monitor</VitalsMonitor.label>
  <VitalsMonitor.description>Build vitals monitors which improve medical outcomes when placed next to hospital beds.</VitalsMonitor.description>

  <Fabrication.label>fabrication</Fabrication.label>
  <Fabrication.description>Build fabrication benches, capable of high-tech projects ranging from component assembly to power armor construction.</Fabrication.description>

  <AdvancedFabrication.label>advanced fabrication</AdvancedFabrication.label>
  <AdvancedFabrication.description>Fabricate advanced components from standard components and other materials.</AdvancedFabrication.description>

  <Cryptosleep.label>cryptosleep casket</Cryptosleep.label>
  <Cryptosleep.description>Construct cryptosleep caskets, which can put living beings in a state of indefinite suspended animation.</Cryptosleep.description>

  <PoweredArmor.label>powered armor</PoweredArmor.label>
  <PoweredArmor.description>Build the power armor and power armor helmets. Note that these also require advanced components.</PoweredArmor.description>

  <ChargedShot.label>pulse-charged munitions</ChargedShot.label>
  <ChargedShot.description>Build weapons which fire pulse-charged munitions for extra damage. Note that these also require advanced components.</ChargedShot.description>

  <Bionics.label>bionics</Bionics.label>
  <Bionics.description>Build high-tech bionic body parts to replace lost limbs and eyes. Requires a skilled doctor to attach.</Bionics.description>


</LanguageData>